Guide to the Urban League of Portland Records 1910-2014
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Audio and Video Materials, 1962-2003; Subgroup 3; 125 video and 30 audio recordings
  - Video, 1981-2003; Series 1
    - Annual Dinner, 1992 (Box-item 30.42)
      DVD (2 of 2) duplicate of VHS recording of July 1992 Annual Dinner (item 43).
    - Annual Dinner, 1992 (Box-item 30.43)
      VHS; recorded and produced by Paragon Cable (2:00:00). Recording of Annual Dinner on July 9, 1992 with the theme of "Celebration of our Youth: Youth Revitalization in Our Community". Cleo Fields, Louisiana State Senator, was the keynote speaker. Also includes footage of James Francesconi, Master of Ceremonies; Kevin Fallen, Urban Leage Board of Directors member; Kyra Parker, Urban League scholarship winner; Tawan Paris, minister; Judith Ramaley; Charles Jordan; Bill Wyatt, Chair of Urban League Board of Directors; Darryl S. Tukufu, President and CEO of the Urban League of Portland; and Michelle Burch, former Southern University student who introduced Cleo Fields. DVD duplicates of this recording are available in the collection (items 41-42).
    - Equal Opportunity Day Dinner, 1993 (Box-item 30.44)
      DVD (1 of 2) duplicate of VHS recording of February 1993 Equal Opportunity Day Dinner (item 46).
    - Equal Opportunity Day Dinner, 1993 (Box-item 30.45)
      DVD (2 of 2) duplicate of VHS recording of February 1993 Equal Opportunity Day Dinner (item 46).
    - Equal Opportunity Day Dinner, 1993 (Box-item 30.46)
      VHS; recorded and produced by Paragon Cable; February 1993 (1:42:00). E. Shelton Hill, longtime Director of the Urban League of Portland, from 1956 to 1973, died several days before the event. Recording includes footabe of Gina Wood, Master of Ceremonies; John Mack, President and CEO of the Los Angeles Urban League, as keynote speaker; Dr. Darryl S. Tukufu, President and CEO of the Urban League of Portland; Carry Clayton, NE Assistant Director, Youth Services Center (signs Black National Anthem); Rev. Robert J. Eaddy, Highland United Church of Christ; Barbara Roberts, Oregon Governor; Vera Katz, Portland Mayor; Daniel Moriarty, Portland Community College; and Robert Ridgely, President and CEO of Northwest Natural Gas Company. Portland Mayor Vera Katz read proclamations declaring February 19, 1993 as Shelly Hill Day and February 25, 1993 as Portland Equal Opporutnity Day. DVD duplicates of this recording are available in the collection (items 44-45).
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1994 (Box-item 30.47)
      VHS, News Coverage of awards. (0:11:00)
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1994 (Box-item 30.48)
      U-matic, Edna Robertson, Fred Stickel, Ed Jenson.
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.49)
      U-matic, February 20, 1996 (0:07:00)
    - Equal Opportunity Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.50)
      VHS; speech footage; February 22, 1996 (1:50:00). The theme was "Building Communities through Education, Employment, and Equality". The program included a video of the Urban League of Portland missions near the end of the dinner event. Keynote speaker was Ron Daly, who spoke of his experience of working his way to the President of Communications for R.R. Donnelly & Sons Co. Footage also includes Brenda Braxton, Master of Ceremonies; Rev. Denis Bell; Dr. Judith Ramaley, Urban League of Portland Co-Chair; Keith Lovett, Fred Meyer vice president and Urban League of Portland Co-Chair; Lawrence J. Dark, President and CEO of Urban League of Portland; Michael Lewellen and Jidi Petre, award presenters; Bill Prows, US West; Avel Gordley, Oregon State Representative; Tony Hopson, Self Entertainment, Inc.; and Gerald McFadden, Volunteers of America. DVD duplicates of this recording are available in the collection (items 53-54).
    - Annual Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.51)
      VHS; recorded and produced by Paragon Cable; July 10, 1996 (1:02:00). The theme was "The Celebration of our Youth". Keynote speaker was Rev. Ron Sailor, Jr. Footage also includes Donna Johnson, Mistress of Ceremonies; James. R. Boehlke, Urban Leage of Portland Board Chair; Kay Toran, Dinner Co-Chair; Hilson and Sweeta Darrow, Whitney M. Young students; Bob Boyer, Oregon Senator and Dinner Co-Chair; and Norma Paulus, Superintendent of Public Instruction. A DVD duplicate of this recording is available in the collection (item 55).
    - Annual Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.52)
      VHS, July 10, 1996 (1:56:00)
    - Equal Opportunity Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.53)
      DVD (1 of 2) duplicate of VHS recording of February 1996 Equal Opportunity Dinner (items 50 and 56).
    - Equal Opportunity Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.54)
      DVD (2 of 2) duplicate of VHS recording of February 1996 Equal Opportunity Dinner (items 50 and 56).
    - Annual Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.55)
      DVD duplicate of VHS recording of July 1996 Annual Dinner (items 51-52).
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1996 (Box-item 30.56)
      VHS, Unedited footage from the Urban League of Portland's Equal Opportunity Dinner. February 22, 1996 (2:01:00) See description of item 50 for contents of the recording. DVD duplicates of this recording are available in the collection (items 53-54).
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, 1998 (Box-item 30.57)
      VHS, speeches (1:12:00)
    - Equal Opportunities Dinner, undated (Box-item 30.58)
      Advertisements for the Urban League of Portland's Equal Opportunities Day Dinner. (0:01:00)
    - Edwin C. Berry, 1989 (Box-item 30.59)
      U-matic, February 7, 1989
    - Free Indeed: A Video Drama About Racism, 1995 (Box-item 30.60)
      VHS, A video that attempts to get youth to think deeply about racism in the USA. (0:25:11)
    - Grandparents Conference, 1994 (Box-item 30.61)
      VHS, News reel about grandparents taking on the role of parents. August 1, 1994 (0:01:53)
    - Grandparent Education, Grandparent Program, 1995 (Box-item 30.62)
      VHS, Talking with Grandparents about how to support their families if they are raising their grandchildren. May 16, 1995 (0:14:20)
    - Grandparents Meeting with Ron Wyden, 1994 (Box-item 30.63)
      VHS, Ron Wyden attends a Grandparents meeting to hear what their concerns are and address some of them. October 20, 1994 (0:44:50)
    - Grandparents Raising Grandchildren, 1994 (Box-item 30.64)
      VHS, A panel of Grandmothers talk about their lives and tricks to raising their grandchildren. (0:28:05)
    - GTE Sponsor, undated (Box-item 30.65)
      Urban League of Portland ad requesting people to sign up and be sponsors for children in need of help. (0:01:30)
    - Hand in Hand: Collected Clips, 1997 (Box-item 30.66)
      VHS, Clips include setting up for the Hand in Hand events at Clackamas Elementary School, the actual assembly, the events afterward, Channel 6 news coverage thereof, Hand in Hand advertisements, and instructional clips of how to help babies learn. (1:09:00)
    - Hand in Hand: For Kids' Sake, undated (Box-item 30.67)
      VHS, 2 different PSAs that urge parents to take part in child's education. (0:01:20)
    - Hand in Hand PSA's, 1996 (Box-item 30.68)
      VHS, English PSAs repeated 3 times, 1 Spanish version, stars Meryl Streep, urges parents to take part in their child's education. August 9, 1996 (0:01:60)
    - Homeless Program, 1987 (Box-item 31.69)
      VHS, Presentation about the Urban League of Portland's homeless program. June 12, 1987 (0:11:00)
    - Interviews: 50th Dinner, tape 1, 1995 (Box-item 31.70)
      Betacam, Don McClave, Bobby Nunn, Hill. September, 1995
    - Interviews: 50th Dinner, tape 2, 1995 (Box-item 31.71)
      Betacam, H.J. Belton Hamilton, Rabbi Emanuel Rose, Kevin Fuller. September, 1995
    - Interviews: 50th Dinner, tape 3, 1995 (Box-item 31.72)
      Betacam, Joy Pruitt, John Holly, Donnie Adair, Myrtle Carr, L. Dark, Barb O'Hare. September, 1995
    - Interviews: Adult Employment Center, undated (Box-item 31.73)
      VHS, Interview with those working at the Urban League of Portland's Adult Employment Center; Lelia, Donna, Nationwide. (0:42:22)
    - Interviews: CTC and Employment Department, undated (Box-item 31.74)
      VHS, Urban League of Portland's Center for Career Development interview. (0:30:40)
    - Interview: Leah Dumas, undated (Box-item 31.75)
      VHS, Leah Dumas is using the Urban League of Portland's Employment Center to look for a job. (0:32:42)
    - Interviews: Myron Clark, tape 1, undated (Box-item 31.76)
      Interview with Myron Clark and his employer. (0:32:49)
    - Interviews: Myron Clark, tape 2, undated (Box-item 31.77)
      Interview with Myron Clark. (0:32:42)
    - Interviews: Nationwide Employee, undated (Box-item 31.78)
      (0:18:59)
    - "Keeping Families Together" Workshop, tape 1, 1994 (Box-item 31.79)
      VHS, An attorney says that a CSD has the right to adopt a grandchild when the parents are unable to provide enough support for their children. (2:03:00 )
    - "Keeping Families Together" Workshop, tape 2, 1994 (Box-item 31.80)
      VHS, Illustrate how books can be used to build "bridges" between people in order to keep families together. (1:48:00 )
    - "Keeping Families Together" Workshop, tape 3, 1994 (Box-item 31.81)
      VHS, Panel discussion about what is breaking families apart and/or keeping them from reconnecting. (1:58:00 )
    - "Keeping Families Together" Workshop, tape 4, 1994 (Box-item 31.82)
      VHS, Workshop on keeping families together, talk about how to help children get out of the adoption system. (1:02:00 )
    - "Keeping Families Together" Workshop, opening speakers, 1994 (Box-item 31.83)
      VHS, (0:52:00) (1:02:00 )
    - "Keeping Families Together" Workshop, Dr. Lenora Poe, 1985 (Box-item 31.84)
      VHS, Dr. Lenora Poe discusses her struggles with raising her daughter. January 5, 1985 (0:47:00 )
    - Kwanza Celebration, 1994 (Box-item 31.85)
      VHS, Discusses the purpose of a Kwanza celebration, adult and senior services center. December 30, 1994 (1:11:06)
    - Leadership Summit, 1995 (Box-item 31.86)
      VHS, Summit explaining how to use technology for leadership, Dr. Darrell Tufuku. October 12, 1995 (1:26:00)
    - Les Brown: "Live Your Dreams", undated (Box-item 31.87)
      VHS, Informational video about Les Brown, Brown gives a motivational speech. (2:11:46)
    - Lowell Jones, undated (Box-item 31.88)
      VHS (0:12:20)
    - Membership Drives: Dr. Darryl Tufuku, 1991 (Box-item 31.89)
      VHS, Video inviting those in need of help to come and join the Urban League. April 24, 1991 (0:01:05)
    - Membership Drives, 1996 (Box-item 31.90)
      VHS, Video of clients. March 6, 1996 (0:06:50)
    - Membership Drives, 1996 (Box-item 31.91)
      VHS, December 23, 1996 (0:05:35)
    - Metro Beat: Civil Rights in Portland, 1992 (Box-item 31.92)
      VHS, Recording of Metro Beat, discuss civil rights in the Portland area, mention Urban League of Portland. July 12, 1992 (1:59:03)
    - Multicultural Senior Fair, undated (Box-item 31.93)
      VHS, A fair for seniors at the Urban League of Portland's Senior center to display foreign cultures. (0:10:27)
    - Namaste Retreat and Conference Center, undated (Box-item 31.94)
      VHS, informational video about the Namaste Conference Center just outside portland (0:04:20)
    - NE Spectrum: Do The Right Thing Day, 1996 (Box-item 31.95)
      VHS, Interview with Lawrence Dark and students of the program. September 18, 1996 (01:00:00)
    - Nike: "Black and White", 1992 (Box-item 31.96)
      VHS, Nike advertisement race relations. May 21, 1992 (0:01:00 )
    - Northwest Focus: Pastor Tellis on the Urban League of Portland, 2001 (Box-item 31.97)
      VHS, Pastor Tellis, a volunteer at the Urban League of Portland talks about the League. February 19, 2011 (0:29:40 )
    - Oregon Peace Institute: "Child Workers", undated (Box-item 31.98)
      VHS, Promote the support of groups fighting for peace across the globe. (0:24:24)
    - One Strike, You're Out! The New Juvenile Crime Law, undated (Box-item 31.99)
      VHS, Rules of Measure 11 are outlined for youth in this information video. (0:08:07)
    - One Stop, undated (Box-item 31.100)
      VHS, Informational video about the Urban League of Portland's One Stop Career Center and other job application centers (0:20:50)
    - Parent Voices, undated (Box-item 31.101)
      VHS, Informational video about the struggles of caring for children when all of the parents in the household work outside the home. (0:16:05)
    - Portland Development Commission: Homestead Program, 1991 (Box-item 31.102)
      VHS, November 4, 1991 (0:06:28)
    - Portland Public Schools Fundraiser, 1996 (Box-item 31.103)
      VHS, Private fundraising drive and march to support public schools in Portland. October 21, 1996
    - Poverty and Urban Sprawl, undated (Box-item 31.104)
      VHS recorded and produced by Paragon Cable (1:00:36). Presents research on poverty and urban sprawl. Minnesota State Representative, Myron Orfields, presents data comparing povery and urban sprawl for the Portland metro area and a Minnesota metro area.
    - Powell, 1997 (Box-item 31.105)
      VHS, John Powell talks at the Urban League about how, in order to change any system, we must understand it's core objective. October 28, 1997 (1:16:57 )
    - PSAs, 1997 (Box-item 31.106)
      VHS, "One Goal," "We're Asking," "Walk the Walk," recruitment Videos for the Corporation for National Service. (0:14:17)
    - Red Cross: "Don't Forget Sherrie", undated (Box-item 31.107)
      VHS, Video about sexual activity and AIDS among teenagers. (0:32:39 )
    - Regional Drug Initiative, 1998 (Box-item 31.108)
      VHS, Informational video about the Regional Drug Initiative, praising it for bringing all concerned parties to the table. January 29, 1998 (0:11:10 )
    - "Say Yes:" Bureau of Labor and Industries, undated (Box-item 31.109)
      VHS, Informational Video about Job Corps and how it helps students. (0:13:08 )
    - State Farm Movie Trailer, undated (Box-item 31.110)
      (0:06:33)
    - "Strive:" 60 Minutes, 1997 (Box-item 31.111)
      VHS, The STRIVE program is discussed and presented in this episode of 60 Minutes. May 4, 1997 (0:026:05 )
    - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1997 (Box-item 31.112)
      VHS, Music video about the summer youth program. (0:17:11)
    - Summer Youth Employment Program, 1997 (Box-item 31.113)
      VHS, Music video about the summer youth program (0:09:13)
    - Teaching Math and Science with Al Roker, undated (Box-item 31.114)
      VHS, Video explaining why math and science should be taught in completely interactive environments. (0:57:26 )
    - "This Hope That You Seed:" New Harvest Foundation, 1996 (Box-item 32.1)
      VHS, Discussion about the treatment of gays, bisexuals, and lesbians with the New Harvest Foundation and how the Foundation is helping these groups of individuals. (0:14:32 )
    - Truancy Officer Mike Cruse, 1997 (Box-item 32.2)
      VHS, October 14, 1997 (0:03:13)
    - Urban League of Portland Fishing Derby, 1994 (Box-item 32.3)
      VHS, (0:54:06)
    - Urban League of Greater Miami: "Back to Basics and Beyond" (Box-item 32.4)
      VHS, ways to help put family back together (0:17:08)
    - Urban League of Portland Youth Service Center, 1992 (Box-item 32.5)
      VHS, Informational video about the ULPDX and the services it provides. (0:22:22)
    - Urban League of Portland, undated (Box-item 32.6)
      U-matic (0:05:00)
    - Urban Rangers, 1991 (Box-item 32.7)
      VHS; (0:10:43). A short documentary, prepared by IBEX Communication, on the U.S. Forest Service's Urban Ranger Project to expose urban youth to the National Forests. The video documents the participation of urban youth in programs to learn about the environment outside of their neighborhood and home and careers such as natural resources.
    - Urban Rangers: Careers in the Forest Service, undated (Box-item 32.8)
      VHS, Video about what one should consider when contemplating a job and why someone should consider joining the Forest Service. (0:10:36 )
    - Welfare Reform, 1997 (Box-item 32.9)
      VHS, Review of how 1997 welfare reforms could impact a fictional family. (0:29:31)
    - Whitney M. Young Jr. Awards Dinner, 2000 (Box-item 32.10)
      VHS, Mission Video for the Los Angeles Urban League. (0:14:44 )
    - Youth Education Sports, 2003 (Box-item 32.11)
      VHS, Pictures and Video of youth participating in sports. April 2003 - October 2003 (0:31:00 )
  - Audio, 1962-1998; Series 2
    Series 2 consists of 27 audiocassette tapes and 3 reel-to-reel sound recordings. The majority of the recordings are of speeches given at the National Urban League Conferences in 1991-1994. For the events and membership drives, the sound recordings are primarily promotional radio advertisements.
    - Events, 1993-1998; Sub-Series 1
      - Career Connections, circa 1990s (Box-item 33.1)
        Promo (00:00:30)
      - Career Connections, March 2, 1993 (Box-item 33.2)
        3 promos, (00:00:30) each
      - Career Connections, March 26, 1998 (Box-item 33.3)
        (00:01:00)
      - Achievement Rally, May 1998 (Box-item 33.4)
    - Membership Drive, July 20, 1993 (Box-item 33.5)
      Promo (00:00:50)
    - National Urban League Conferences, 1991-1994; Sub-Series 2
      - "Onward! To a Decade of Difference! Great Curriculum Robbery", circa 1990s (Box-item 33.6)
        Speakers: J. Jerome Harris, Irving S. Hamer, Jr.
      - "Are We Corp. Professionals who just Happen to be Black or Blacks who Happen to be Corp. Professionals?", 1991 (Box-item 33.7)
      - "Building Parent/Principle/Teacher Partnerhips: A Look at School-Based Management", 1991 (Box-item 33.8)
      - "Schools for African-American Males: Will They Work?", 1991 (Box-item 33.9)
      - "Institutional Roles in Developing African-American Children", August 2, 1993 (Box-item 33.10)
        Honored: Richard W. Riley, Evelyn K. Moons, Cornel West
      - "African-American Self-Development", August 2, 1993 (Box-item 33.11)
        Alvin F. Pouissant
      - "Lifestyles of African-American Youth, August 2, 1993; 2 tapes (Box-item 33.12-13)
      - "What Works in Education: Beyond the Rhetoric", August 3, 1993; 2 tapes (Box-item 33.14-15)
      - "Progress Through Pulpits", August 3, 1993 (Box-item 33.16)
      - "Statehood for the District of Colombia", August 3, 1993 (Box-item 33.17)
        Reverend Jesse L. Jackson, Mayor Sharon P. Kelly
      - "Family Session", July 24, 1994 (Box-item 33.18)
        Inspiration Message: Reverend Cecil Williams
      - "Mobilizing Parents and Communities for Educational Excellence", July 25, 1994 (Box-item 33.19)
      - "Business and Labor Luncheon: A Sense of Community", July 26, 1994 (Box-item 33.20)
        Randall L. Tobias
      - "Child Care: Meeting Community Needs", July 27, 1994 (Box-item 33.21)
    - Outside Produced, 1990-1994; Sub-Series 3
      - "The Best of Grass Root News", circa 1990s (Box-item 33.22)
        30 minutes each side
      - "Endangered Species: Case Studies on Environmental Racism--US/Mexico Border, Hawaii, Alaska and Puerto Rico", circa 1990s (Box-item 33.23)
        Southwest Media Productions, 28 minutes
      - "Prejudice Puzzle: Native American Youth/Education", circa 1990s (Box-item 33.24)
      - "Street Academy", circa 1990s (Box-item 33.25)
        aired on KBOO
    - Promos (general), undated, March 10, 1994; 2 tapes (Box-item 33.26-33.27)
      4 promos, (00:00:30) each
    - "New Thrust" Radio Promo, undated; 1 reel-to-reel audiotape (Box-item 34.1)
      James Brown, one minute spot announcement
    - "Rights of Man" Program, June 24, 1962; 1 reel-to-reel audiotape (Box-item 34.2)
    - The Urban League of Ptld, undated; 1 reel-to-reel audiotape (Box-item 34.3)